A Guide to the Records of First Lady Lisa Collis, 2002-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of First Lady Lisa Collis, 2002-2005
The Library of Virginia
42420
0.70 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the First Lady.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Margaret Hughson, Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, accession 42420, transferred on 18 January 2006 and accessioned 19 January 2006.
Biographical Information
Lisa Collis, First Lady of Virginia from 2002-2006, was born in Pensacola, Florida. She grew up in a Navy family and lived in seven states before settling in Falls Church, Virginia. Ms. Collis attended George C. Marshall High School, earned her Bachelor's degree in Biology at the University of Virginia and received her Masters degree in Public Health at the University of Texas. Her professional career has included health outreach to migrant farmer workers with the East Coast Migrant Health project and policy work with the World Bank, where she focused on food and nutrition issues and on AIDS assistance for Africa.
As First Lady, Ms. Collis devoted her time to supporting initiatives related to the well-being of Virginia's children, the environment and the arts. She traveled throughout the state advocating for parenting support programs.
Continuing with the spirit of public service begun in her private life, Ms.Collis served on several charitable boards and organizations, and supported efforts to improve children's health and quality early learning. She also continued her work with the Collis-Warner Foundation, established jointly with her husband, Governor Mark R. Warner. They are the parents of three daughters.
-Source: Web site of First Lady Lisa Collis
Scope and Content
The First Lady's Itinerary records are housed in 2 boxes. The collection is arranged chronologically. These records include event invitations, event briefing forms, correspondence, photographs, and prepared remarks for Lisa Collis. These records document Lisa Collis' official appearences as First Lady during the term of Virginia Governor Mark R. Warner (2002-2006).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. First Lady's Itinerary
Related Material
Web site of First Lady Lisa Collis, 2005-2006 part of the Virginia's Political Landscape, Fall 2005, Web collection.
Contents List
- Series I. First Lady's Itinerary, 2002-2005., Extent: 0.70 cu. ft. (2 boxes).
  - Annual Arts Advocacy Day Breakfast, 2002 January 24. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Richmond History Center Luncheon, 2002 February 14. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - TACTS 12th Annual Fashion Show and Silent Auction, 2002 March 9. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ribbon Cutting, Community Health Education Center at VCU, 2002 March 11. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Child Abuse Prevention Kick Off, 2002 April 4. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Epilepsy Foundation Calendar Presentation, 2002 April 18. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Foster Care Forum (Alexandria), 2002 May 4. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pfizer "Share Card Rollout," 2002 July 18. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Discover Historic Richmond, 2002 September 21. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Read Aloud to a Child, 2002 October 24. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Virginia CASA Conference, 2002 November 8. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - YWCA of Richmond Storybook Heroes, 2002 November 25. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Read for 2003, 2002 December 6. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meals on Wheels Groundbreaking Ceremony, 2003 March 4. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1st Annual Healthy Families Celebration of Success Ceremony, 2003 April 29. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Community Leadership Network Luncheon, 2003 October 2. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - AARP Virginia's Active for Life Walking Campaign, 2003 October 7. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ribbon Cutting, Fredericksburg's Historic Market Square, 2003 October 30. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Knockout Abuse, 2003 November 6. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Memorial Child Guidence Clinic, 2003 November 12. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Read for 2004, 2003 December 5. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - CARITAS Celebrity Server Dinner, 2004 February 17. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - NoVA Scan Awards Luncheon, 2004 April 1. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - UVA Dinner Honoring Janet Napolitano, 2004 April 21. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Fine Arts Festival, 2004 May 16. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "I Believe I Can Fly" Program, Great Bridge Intermediate School, 2004 May 28. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Arlington Public Schools Award, 2004 October 13. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Virginia Action for Healthy Kids, Roanoke Fox News Interview, 2004 November 1. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Richmond SCAN Advocacy Center Opening, 2004 November 10. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Luxford Elementary School Award, 2004 December 10. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Schooner Christening, 2004 December 10. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Read 2005, 2004 December 3. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Heifer International Kick-off, 2005 January 11. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - YMCA Key Leaders Luncheon, 2005 January 24. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - PTA Lobby Day, 2005 January 31. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Give Kids a Smile" Day, 2005 February 4. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - CVC Thanks! Luncheon, 2005 March 2. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Read Across America Day, Stonehouse Elementary School, 2005 March 4. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Read to Lead, Millwood Elementary School, 2005 March 21. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Keys to Engagement-A Child Abuse Prevention Conference, 2005 April 4. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Week of the Young Child Open House and Art Show, 2005 April 6. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Epilepsy Foundation, 2005 April 20. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chesterfield County PEP Grant Recipient Meeting, 2005 April 27. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Governor's Early Childhood Summit, 2005 May 13. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Aschiana-Afghan Children's Fundraiser, 2005 May 14. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Keep Safe Internet Safety Launch, 2005 May 17. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - WFNR Radio Interview, I Keep Safe, 2005 May 24. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Employer Strategy Session of the Governor's Summit on Early Childhood, 2005 May 25. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Richmond Memory Walk PSA, 2005 June 22. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Women For Kaine Event, Jefferson Hotel, Richmond, 2005 August 24. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Child Advocacy Center Event, 2005 September 20. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - A Healthy Bay for Healthy Kids: Cooking with Virginia's First Lady, 2005 October 4. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Child and Family Services-Eastern Shore, 2005 October 19. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Association of School Nurses, 2005 October 21. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Women for Kaine Rally, 2005 November 3. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Art Museum of Western Virginia Women's Luncheon, 2005 November 10. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Read for 2006, 2005 December 2. (Box 2, Folder 23)